Life can only be understood backwards, but we have to live it forwards.
Memoir of a Snail is a animation, drama, comedy film directed by Adam Elliot.
Forcibly separated from her twin brother when they are orphaned, a melancholic misfit learns how to
find confidence within herself amid the clutter of misfortunes and everyday life.
Grace (voice), played by Sarah Snook.
Gilbert (voice), played by Kodi Smit-McPhee.
Pinky (voice), played by Jacki Weaver.
Ruth Appleby (voice), played by Magda Szubanski.
Percy Pudel (voice), played by Dominique Pinon.
Ken (voice), played by Tony Armstrong.
Memoir of a Snail is a 2024 Australian adult stop-motion animated
tragicomedy film written, produced and directed by Adam Elliot.
It stars the voices of Sarah Snook, Kodi Smit-McPhee, Eric Bana, Magda Szubanski,
Dominique Pinon, Tony Armstrong, Paul Capsis, Nick Cave, and Jacki Weaver.
The film's plot, which is loosely inspired by Elliot's own life, follows the trials and
tribulations in the life of lonely misfit Grace Pudel, from childhood to adulthood.
The film had its world premiere at the 2024 Annecy International Animation Film Festival on 10
June 2024, and was released in Australia by Madman Entertainment on 17 October 2024.
The film received critical acclaim and was nominated for Best Animated Feature at the 97th Academy Awards, the
second R-rated animated film to be nominated after Anomalisa (2015), another stop-motion film.
The film explores themes of depression, difficult childhood,
death of father, stop motion, foster family.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.